The harder the life, the sweeter the song.
Crazy Heart is a drama, music, romance film directed by Scott Cooper.
When reporter Jean Craddock interviews Bad Blake—an alcoholic, seen-better-days country music legend—they connect,
and the hard-living crooner sees a possible saving grace in a life with Jean and her young son.
Bad Blake, played by Jeff Bridges.
Jean Craddock, played by Maggie Gyllenhaal.
Wayne, played by Robert Duvall.
Tommy Sweet, played by Colin Farrell.
Bill Wilson, played by Tom Bower.
Jack Greene, played by Paul Herman.
Crazy Heart is a 2009 American drama film, written and directed
by Scott Cooper in his feature directorial debut.
Based on the 1987 novel of the same name by Thomas Cobb, the
story was inspired by country singer Hank Thompson.
Starring Jeff Bridges, Maggie Gyllenhaal, Colin Farrell, and Robert Duvall, the film follows an alcoholic country singer
and songwriter who tries to turn his life around after beginning a relationship with a young journalist.
Bridges, Farrell, and Duvall also sing in the film.
Filming took place in 2008 throughout New Mexico,
as well as Houston and Los Angeles.
Original music for the film was composed by T Bone
Burnett, Stephen Bruton, and Ryan Bingham.
It was dedicated to Bruton, who died the same year the film was made.
The film was produced by Country Music Television and was originally acquired by Paramount Vantage for a
direct-to-video release, but was later purchased by Fox Searchlight Pictures for theatrical release.
Crazy Heart opened in theaters in the United States on December 16, 2009.
From its $7 million budget, it amassed domestic earnings of $39.5 million
plus $7.9 international for a worldwide total of $47.4 million.
The film was met with critical acclaim and received three nominations at the 82nd Academy Awards, winning Best
Actor for Bridges and Best Original Song for "The Weary Kind", written by Bingham and Burnett.
The film explores themes of journalist, taxi, country music, guitar, musician.
The tone is uplifting and emotional and thought_provoking.